italychronicles.com 2019-06-17

# Privacy Policy

### **Italy Chronicles’ Privacy Statement**

**Who We Are**

ItalyChronicles.com is run by Alex Roe who is based in Milan, Italy. You can contact him here: [Contact](http://italychronicles.com/contact/)

**Data Breaches Detected**

None – 24 May 2018.

#### **Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, ItalyChronicles.com collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. ItalyChronicles.com’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how ItalyChronicles.com’s visitors use its website. From time to time, ItalyChronicles.com may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

ItalyChronicles.com also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. ItalyChronicles.com does not use such information to identify its visitors however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

#### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to ItalyChronicles.com’s website choose to interact with ItalyChronicles.com in ways that require ItalyChronicles.com to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that ItalyChronicles.com gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, I ask visitors who use my commenting system when it is active to provide a name and email address. In each case, ItalyChronicles.com collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfil the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with ItalyChronicles.com.

ItalyChronicles.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Where we send your data**

In the course of the operation of this website, web analytics data may be transferred to Google.com. This data has been anonymised using the Google Analytics [ga(‘set’, ‘anonymizeIp’, true)](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/field-reference#anonymizeIp) feature. Furthermore, data added by visitors adding comments or by using this site’s contact system will be contained in a database located in the United Kingdom (in London) which is where this website is hosted. The group behind the hosting company is StudioPress which has an excellent reputation for security. Indeed, this site is protected by a security system that is always on except on rare occasions when the system is temporarily deactivated for technical reasons. The security system reactivates itself if it is not reactivated manually.

In addition, this website uses an https connection for the secure processing of user data as well as to protect visitor privacy and provide added security.

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Backup copies of this website are carried out by Automattic’s VaultPress service.

**How we protect your data**

Google Analytics data is anonymised. Other data is encrypted using https. Security systems provided by this website’s hosting service help prevent unauthorised access to this website’s data.

**What data breach procedures we have in place**

In the event of a data breach, italychronicles.com’s owner Alex Roe will be advised by this website’s hosting company. If identifiable personal data has been taken in the period after 24 May 2018, all reasonable attempts will be taken to notify users or visitors affected either via email or via a message that will appear on this page.

In addition, to find out what, if any, personally identifiable data has been taken, the [Privacy Centre](http://italychronicles.com/privacy-2/) can be used to find out, what, if any, personally identifiable data relating to a visitor or user of this website has been acquired.

**What third parties we receive data from**

ItalyChronicles.com may used data from Amazon Afilliates schemes to determine the content of new posts. The data is interpreted manually, and does not contain any personally identifiable information. To determine what data Amazon,com and Amazon.co.uk holds on you, contact Amazon.

**What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data**

Automated decision making is used by the website’s top ten posts system which monitors post views and adjusts the list of the most popular posts. No personally identifiable information is collected during the process.

Automated decision making is used by this website’s related post system which is provided by Contextly, a third party service. [Contextly’s privacy policy is here](https://contextly.com/privacy/).

**Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**How Long We Retain Your Data**

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

For users that are paying subscribers to our website, personal information is stored by Tinypass, part of Piano – the system that manages paying subscribers. Paying subscribers can manage their personal information by logging into the Tinypass system. Tinypass is a separate organisation to ItalyChronicles.com which does not control the way in which data provided by Tinypass is used. [The Tinypass-Piano privacy policy is here.](https://piano.io/privacy-policy/)

**What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. Visit our [privacy centre](http://italychronicles.com/privacy-2/) for more information.

#### **Advertising**

ItalyChronicles.com uses third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit this website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Please note that ItalyChronicles.com is part of the **Google Adsense** advertising program which means that Google and/or its partners collect some information about visitors to Italy Chronicles.

You may read more about the information collection system used here:  [DoubleClick DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx):

_**Please also note**_ the following information relating to advertising displayed on ItalyChronicles.com via the Google Adsense advertising program.

  1. Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site.
  2. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to ItalyChronicles.com and other sites on the Internet.
  3. Visitors to ItalyChronicles.com who are concerned about privacy issues **may opt out** of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

#### Aggregated Statistics

ItalyChronicles.com may collect statistics about the behaviour of visitors to its website. However, ItalyChronicles.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

#### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

ItalyChronicles.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organisations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on ItalyChronicles.com’s behalf or to provide services available at ItalyChronicles.com’s website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organisations may be located outside of your home country; by using ItalyChronicles.com’s website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

Alex Roe of ItalyChronicles.com will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors, and affiliated organisations, as described above, ItalyChronicles.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when ItalyChronicles.com believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of ItalyChronicles.com, third parties, or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a ItalyChronicles.com website and have supplied your email address, ItalyChronicles.com may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with ItalyChronicles.com and our products. I primarily use my blog to communicate this type of information, so I expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send me a request (for example via an email or via the commenting system), I reserve the right to publish it in order to help me clarify or respond to your request. ItalyChronicles.com takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

#### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in to ItalyChronicles.com, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

When you log in to ItalyChronicles.com, as a paying subscriber we will also set up several cookies to save your login information. Paying subscriber login cookies last until you logout.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**What are Cookies?**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. ItalyChronicles.com uses cookies to help ItalyChronicles.com identify and track visitors in order to reduce levels of unsolicited email. ItalyChronicles.com visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies _**before**_ using ItalyChronicles.com’s website, with the drawback that certain features of ItalyChronicles.com’s website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

You can find details of the cookies used by ItalyChronicles.com – site cookies and third party cookies by visiting the [Privacy Preferences](http://italychronicles.com/privacy-2/privacy-preferences/) page and clicking on the Privacy Preferences button. You may need to allow popups to be able to see the information.

#### Amazon Affiliation

ItalyChronicles.com is affiliated to Amazon.com and Amazon.co.uk which means this web site may earn commissions on sales of products listed on Amazon.com and Amazon.co.uk if purchases are made.

### Italian Privacy Laws

The personal data of the involved party will be processed by Alex Roe the holder of the ItalyChronicles.com domain, using automated means and other means, in compliance with the provisions of the Italian Legislative Decree n. 196 dated June 30th, 2003 – Privacy Law, for the following purposes:

(i) for performing any and all activities relating to the relationship with the involved party and providing all information, assistance and services requested by the involved party. To that end your personal data may in very rare circumstances be provided to third parties having a contractual relationship with Alex Roe, even if such parties are incorporated outside the European Union, and will be communicated to the persons or entities responsible for or in charge of the personal data treatment nominated by the owner of the ItalyChronicles.com domain Alex Roe;

(ii) for promotional, commercial, and information activities regarding the involved person. To that end your personal data may be provided in rare circumstances by ItalyChronicles.com domain holder Alex Roe to companies having a contractual relationship with ItalyChronicles.com domain holder Alex Roe, even those incorporated outside European Union, and will be communicated to the persons or entities responsible for or in charge with the personal data treatment appointed by said companies.

**The personal data will not be propagated.**  
The provision of your data for the purposes stated in paragraph (i) is optional. Should such data be withheld, you will not be allowed to receive the assistance, information and/or services requested. The provision of your data for the purposes stated in paragraph (ii) is optional. Should such data be withheld, you will not be allowed to receive information about the commercial and/or promotional activities organized by Alex Roe and his partners.

As involved party, you have the rights expressed in art. 7 of the D.Lgs. June 30, 2003, n. 196. Regarding the expression of these rights, including knowing which persons responsible for personal data treatment have been appointed by Alex Roe, the involved party may send a written communication to contact AT italychronicles DOT com.

### Your online shopping can support ItalyChronicles.com.

Alex Roe the owner of ItalyChronicles.com has agreements with independent online retailers that enable visitors to ItalyChronicles.com to purchase books, and other merchandise mentioned on ItalyChronicles.com through third party sites. A portion of that revenue is designated to ItalyChronicles.com.

Purchases made through these third party sites are subject to the policies and procedures of those sites. Order fulfilment and customer service relating to orders placed at any of those third party sites, including the collection of applicable sales taxes, are the sole responsibility of such sites. Any concerns regarding order fulfilment, customer service, privacy policies or other issues relating to these third party online retail sites should be directed to the Webmaster or site administrator of the site.

**How do these relationships work?**

Alex Roe of ItalyChronicles.com has agreements with a number of online retailers to offer a wider variety of merchandise through links on our site. Purchases made through these links result in a portion of your total purchase being given to ItalyChronicles.com, called a revenue share. These funds are used to support ItalyChronicles.com online. ItalyChronicles.com only receives this money if you shop through one of the special links on on ItalyChronicles.com. Once you’ve entered the third party site, ItalyChronicles.com receives a revenue share from all products you purchase during that visit.

**Why shop through ItalyChronicles.com?**

The links provided on ItalyChronicles.com are specially coded to designate you as an ItalyChronicles.com supporter. This is the only way to ensure that your purchase goes to supporting ItalyChronicles.com.

**What happens to my personal information?**

When shopping at one of the third party retail sites with which ItalyChronicles.com has a relationship, you are subject to that site’s privacy and security policies.

### **Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, ItalyChronicles.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in ItalyChronicles.com’s sole discretion. ItalyChronicles.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

**Last Update:** 24th May, 2018.
